<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sir. Bøøps</title>
    <description>Just a blog for a bored internet user.</description>
    <link>https://boops.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://boops.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:43:59 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 12:43:59 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolling Release Vs Planned Releases</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A rolling release is as it sounds it is a single version of a version-less release. Sounds weird right? well let me put it into easier to understand context for you. You might know about Arch Linux if you don’t it is a rolling release Distro that means there is only the initial release version of Arch That is always kept up to date. See a single version of a version-less release! simple right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now Planned release or versioned(?) releases also are as they sound a Distro that has been planned to have specific versions of software like Ubuntu version X will only ever get version X of software with security updates so by the EoL (End Of Life) of Ubuntu X you will still have version X.Y of that specific piece of software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you have an idea of what they are let’s go over some of the pros and cons of each. Starting with planned releases some of the major benefits that come with it are the assurance that a system updating won’t break your system. This coming from the fact that most/all packages in a planned release have a specific version that they stick for for the life of the OS. That little fact also makes planned releases widely used on servers because every time you update the last thing you want is some dependency breaking for another piece of software leading to downtime. On the topic of negatives lets also look into some downsides of planned releases such as the fact that you can get stuck with older software a good example of this is OpenSSL if the version of the Distro you are running is only ever using openSSL 1.0.1 and you need 1.0.2 for example looks like you’re compiling or upgrading your OS to the next version to get that update. This also rolls nicely into my next point if you’re using a planned release then it will become outdated meaning that you will have to do a reinstall or really risk it and try an in place upgrade but which ever of the two you choose they both end with you eventually end up with you upgrading your box and having to redo it or pray the in place upgrade works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolling back into a more positive vibe (Ha!) lets look at some of the upsides of a rolling release. The first big one is you never have to reinstall once you install the Distro you’ll only ever have to pacman -Syu (Arch update all command) and you’ll have the latest version of everything available for your Distro. This also goes into the next big point of you’ll always have the latest and greatest versions of software a perfect example of this is at the time of writing this the RX480 has just recently been released and the new kernel that has the drivers built in is 4.7. Now if you’re on a rolling release it might take hours or days to get that update but you still know it’s going to be coming pretty quickly this is a huge contrast to a planned release Distro as they have already decided on a specific kernel version for there Distro leaving the users that want/need that drive compiling the kernel themselves or sitting on the beta/alpha branch of their Distro hoping it comes quickly. Wow all this sounds so nice! Well this is where the bad news about rolling releases comes in as you might’ve guessed since it might only take a day~ish to get the newest kernel there is not a lot if any testing being done forcing you to test it and forcing you to hope that the next time you update that some broken patch hasn’t been issued with a large security hole or even an update that as the Arch joke goes “Broke my xorg.conf again”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now personally for my personal home computer i use Void/Arch/Gentoo all rolling releases as for me i don’t mind if i get issues while updating actually sometimes it’s fun to get issues as it can lead to you learning something that you might not have unless this happened. That being said the value to a planned release is huge and unless you have time to tinker with your system or always want/need the latest packages i would suggest you use a planned release as like i said above they are usually very stable and dependable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading! if you have any issues, questions or anything else please feel free to contact me via &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#098;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Sir_Boops&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 09:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/07/27/09-49-rolling-release-vs-planned-releases.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/07/27/09-49-rolling-release-vs-planned-releases.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Switching From Bind9 to PowerDNS4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong their was and still is nothing wrong with bind it’s fast, efficient and supports everything you could want out of a basic DNS server. Catch that? a basic DNS server and that is where my issue with bind comes from their &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a mysql backend for bind floating out their some where on the internets but trying to find documentation or an official repository for it proved much to hard to find. This combining with the fact that i had to setup cron jobs to keep re signing the domains for DNSSEC set the stage nicely for for powerdns to come and sweep me up. My initial tests with it where quite lack luster as while i was trying to set it up before i found the official docs for powerdns and trust me for setting up a mysql backend you want those docs unless you feel like upping the log-level to 7 and trying to reverse engineer from that. Before you ask yes i did that to figure out how SRV records are stored in the database and also yes i feel quite dumb now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back on track i found powerdns while searching how to setup bind with a mysql backend and after finally setting it up all i can say is wow DNSSEC is a dream with powerdns and i do mean that to the fullest extent as if you are to scroll back in this blog you will see a post on how to setup DNSSEC with bind and it’s quite a long post where as with powerdns it’s one command! All of that goes with out saying that it auto re signs the domains so once it’s setup and running you never have to touch it again and to my surprise the MYSQL backend is quite efficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So would i recommend you to start on powerdns? No simply because the features i’m drooling over in this article aren’t useful to most people an amazing example of this is out of the top 50 websites on paypal has DNSSEC enabled where as a large majority have full or partial IPv6 support now comparing that with smaller sites like blogs for example how many have IPv6 at all despite the huge push on website owners to use IPv6. Now put that into terms for DNSSEC a tech that a majority haven’t heard of built on a tech that most people touch once then never again! All that being said if you want the joy of knowing that you are on the cutting edge of DNS tech and the peace the comes with knowing it is now much harder to hijack your domain then yes use powerdns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question, concern or just want to tell me something? &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#098;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;email me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2016 14:27:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/07/21/14-27-switching-from-bind9-to-powerdns4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/07/21/14-27-switching-from-bind9-to-powerdns4.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SSH Tunnels</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You may have heard about SSH tunneling. About what it can do how it works etc etc. But today I’m going to show you the three main tunnel/super useful tunnels that you can quickly setup over SSH.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Dynamic setup using the -D &lt;port number=&quot;&quot;&gt; flag while opening the SSH connection it sets the SSH connection to also act as a socks server allowing applications that support socks (Firefox for instance) to connect and communicate through the remote server. This can be quickly used to tunnel your connection to your home for instance allowing you to securely browse your local network while anywhere securely. This can also be used to quickly jump over firewalls on public Wi-Fi being said though they would have to allow SSH in the first place. Full example of how to create and use a dynamic tunnel is `ssh &lt;user&gt;@&amp;lt;address&amp;gt; -D &lt;port number=&quot;&quot;&gt;` That will open the connection then once you login you tell the application the supports socks to connect to `127.0.0.1:&lt;port number=&quot;&quot; you=&quot;&quot; used=&quot;&quot;&gt;` and their you go an encrypted tunnel to your server that you can use to browse the web!&lt;/port&gt;&lt;/port&gt;&lt;/user&gt;&lt;/port&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Local port forwarding. This can take a minute to wrap your head around as it’s like normal port forwarding just in reverse as it forwards the defined port from your end to the server you are connecting to so for example when you local forward port 7777 when a process on your system tries to connect to *:7777 it will connect though the SSH tunnel to the remote host. Kinda confusing right? But this does have it uses and the best example that comes to mind is syncthing. Syncthing has a webgui that allows it to administer it and of course for security reasons you would not want that facing the internet as someone will find it and attempt to brute force it so that way i secured mine while still using a password i can remember is by making it only serve the webgui over localhost then use a local port forward on my client to connect to it over a secure session. Now to use local port forwarding you use the -L flag as such &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;address&amp;gt; -L &amp;lt;local ip to listen on&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;local port&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;remote ip to forward to&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;remote port to forward to&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; Remebemer that the if you do not define the first IP it will default to 127.0.0.1 or ::1.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remote port forwarding. This type of tunnel is super handy for tons of applications such as temporary port forwarding if your network has a device that you can SSH into or even permanent open ports if you use a program like autossh to keep the connection open so you could have a webserver in your home without using your personal IP or if you have a DHCP address this would also allow you to connect to your homes internal network via a static IP on a VPS! To setup remote port forwarding is only slightly harder to do then the previous two as inside of your sshd_config file you have to set &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GatewayPorts yes&lt;/code&gt; and if you don’t do this the connection won’t work. Now the command to use remote port forwarding as i’m guessing you guessed by now is -R used in the same format as local port forwading so &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ssh &amp;lt;user&amp;gt;@&amp;lt;address&amp;gt; -R &amp;lt;local ip to listen on&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;local port&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;remote ip to forward to&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;remote port to forward to&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally to end this all off i’d just like to remind you to use the -v flag to, It stands for verbose and can really really help you in trying to figure out way you are unable to use your SSH tunnel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question, concern or just want to tell me somthing? &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#098;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;email me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 09:26:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/07/15/09-26-ssh-tunnels.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/07/15/09-26-ssh-tunnels.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IPv6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, this will be a listed rant article as people who know how computers work in a basic sense know IPv4 but still have no clue as to how IPv6 works and the people who should have taught them IE teachers usually just skip over it with the common excuses that i’m going to list off below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Its usage is not wide spread enough”. Let me start my response to this with AHHHHHH…Ok i don’t think many of the people who say this think it though to its logical end as why would a company put in the effort into going dual stack or IPv6 only of only 10%~ of their customers are using it? This one hurts more then anything from the reason above as this also means that a large chunk of admins in the world. And that’s how you end up with Amazons Route 53 setup IPv4 only DNS.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“It’s not as safe!” This comes from the fact that a long time ago when you would allow IPv6 auto-configuration it would allow anyone who knew your IPv6 address to get your devices MAC address. Not to downplay this as it is a real issue it has since been solved via IPv6 privacy extensions that as far as I’ve seen basically every IPv6 enabled device has at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“It’s Hard!” I am not quote sure what one hurts more this or point one. Most of the people i know as soon as they are having network issues disable IPv6 which in most cases is quite funny as most people also do not have IPv6 in their house meaning they are disabling something that is already not there. But back on track now, I will concede that when you first look at an IPv6 address it can be long and scary IE the IPv4 &amp;amp; 6 for this page are 167.114.153.91 &amp;amp; 2607:5300:100:200::704. So yes it may look hard if you are just starting with it but remember what else was hard? learning IPv4 but now that you know IPv4 IPv6 will be quite easy to learn and once you start using it you may like i have even start liking it more!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Not as much control over devices” This one nicely ties into the theme of a lot of admins are very lazy just like point three was alluding towards. As this boils down to you haven’t used IPv6 enough or at least explored it enough yet as in my own experience i have been able to do everything i would usually do with DHCP with IPv6 RAs&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now my finial words on this are tl;dr don’t be a lazy admin just because IPv4 works doesn’t mean you should not at minimum get your back end systems running dual stack or if you’re feeling adventurous your whole network running IPv6 as doing that would help kill point one of the list. and finally if you’re a teacher or anyone teaching people IP works please please please also teach IPv6 after IPv4 as if more people know how it works it will up the adoption rate massively for company’s!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question, concern or just want to tell me somthing? &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#098;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;email me!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 08:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/07/11/08-55-ipv6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/07/11/08-55-ipv6.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why You Shouldn&#39;t Use A VPN Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You never know. /post&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No but on a more serious note you have no idea who really has access to the “wires” that you are using and for a moment lets say their is one VPN provider that is 100% true to their word of they track nothing log nothing and they are perfectly secure (Yes i know this is not possible but this is just an example) unless you are using full ipv6 and if you’re reading this there is a 90%~ percent chance (based of google ipv6 stats) that you’re not using it you’ll be sharing that ipv4 with a whole lot of other people meaning that you’ll likely hit every spam filter on any site you go to with one and there is a good chance that you’ll be blocked from some or even many sites not because you have done something malicious towards the site but from the fact that the ip you’re using has a really high chance of being on blacklists from being a know VPN exit node. Phew and remember that is in a best case scenario when you start to factor in things like Well you don’t truly know who is watching the connection and if and arnt logging it plus if they are in the US they could have been issued a gag order by the government preventing them from telling you that the government is watching you (Hi NSA Bot!). Now at this point you might be thinking oh god this might be happening to me or holy crap take your tin foil hat off! To which i reply i just got it fitted! but yes as the only true way to obtain true privacy is to pay for a dedicated server with bitcoin you mined and only connect though public hot spots with a long range antennae and while a few might &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; stallman &lt;em&gt;cough&lt;/em&gt; might do something like this or more even i know that 99.99999% of you will never even attempt to mimic that setup. Now to the original group of people thinking oh god maybe this is happening to me! Never fear an moderately easy fix is here called openvpn or a easy way to allow you to host your own VPN server/client setup without using SSH tunnels as fun as they are. What are the daw back of this setup? well alot of VPS/KVM Hosts don’t allow VPN software in the first place so you’ll have to find one that does near you so you can play games even under the VPN with little to no difference to your ping. Then for the up sides remember that ipv6 i was taking about? does your ISP not offer it yet but you want it? Well if you can find a dual stack host you can easily route public addresses though the VPN tunnel or even use NAT. i know someone shuddered reading that! Overall if you value your privacy in any from or even just want to for IPv6 i would suggest OpenVPN as you can only trust your self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, comments or anything feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#098;&amp;#108;&amp;#111;&amp;#103;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 19:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/06/26/why-you-shouldnt-use-a-vpn-service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/06/26/why-you-shouldnt-use-a-vpn-service.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arch As A Server</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I can hear some Linux server administrators screaming in the distance. Using bleeding edge software in production is always risky as it could break your application or production flow or have security vulnerablys. So why do it then? Simple want that fancy feature that for example NGINX added? Well if you’re using Debian looks like you’re compiling NGINX or waiting for around a year in my experience which if you want something like HTTP/2 that’s quite the wait for such a simple little feature no? Now if you use arch as your server box this also gives you access to the AUR (Arch User Repo) and if you’ve used this before you know that this means that you’ll almost never have to manually compile anything and thanks to pacaur pacman that includes AUR and with that it brings pacaur -Syu and if you haven’t used pacman before that’s full system update so this means even if it’s not inside the arch repos you can get and compile it off the AUR all automatically! All of this and I’ve not even mentioned the best part Arch is a minimal distro this means it starts with almost nothing and you have to add everything that you want no this may sound annoying but it’s actually a bonus as you don’t have to worry that something that you never installed in vulnerable to an attack and you don’t even know you have that package installed. So overall If you want to use Arch as a server OS i would suggest you do BUT only if you have an idea of what you’re doing. Other wise i would say stick to Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 10:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/06/21/10-55-arch-as-a-server.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/06/21/10-55-arch-as-a-server.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trying OpenSUSE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why Yes, I do switch distributions quite a bit and by quite a bit i mean i may have went though around four today trying to find one where i liked the look of the base installed desktop. Yes i know that i can just grab a minimal version of any distro i want and throw a good desktop environment on top of it but that’s work and i wanted something easy that worked pretty well out of the box. This is why i decided to try OpenSuSE as last time i used it (Granted that was inside of a VM) it worked great out of the box and looked amazing as it uses KDE plasma and plasma is so sexy but getting back to trying to install openSUSE. The first issue i came across was my own fault but I’m still going to complain because it’s dumb that you can’t do that and by that i mean install from the live DVD. Why? i have zero idea. Now before you say anything no i did not read any of the red text on the page before downloading and writing it to a USB but still come on you should be able to install from a live DVD and not just the net installer. That actually leads me perfectly into my second point the net installer. Wow it is slow to start Yes i know my internet is slow at an amazing six down and one up but holy crap I’m talking 20+ minutes just for the dam installer to get to the initial splash screen with no progress bars! That while annoying i can live though. Now as i go along in the installer i get to the point where i have to partition my drives dam I’m not sure if I’m slow today but that screen took me a good five~ish minutes to figure out. But after that you got it running right? Nope i left the installer to download and partition one and a half hours later it was still on the same step so i re did that whole process again two more times got the same result and said screw it and installed Ubuntu 16.04 for now. Now i do plan on trying opensuse again but perhaps on it’s next net installer release as i have a funny feeling that this one is quite buggy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 18:46:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/06/13/18-46-trying-opensuse.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/06/13/18-46-trying-opensuse.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From VoidLinux To Antergos Linux</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s distro hopping time again but i must say i was kinda sad to move away from Void as that was quite fun to learn about plus void was pretty stable for being a bleeding edge rolling release but time goes on and i decided to try Antergos now because i don’t read that much about a distro before switching to it as it’s more fun to just jump and go for it it hit me as a surprise that Antergos was just a fancy installer for Arch Linux whoa. Now this is far from a bad thing as arch is also a very good and the only one that could out rank void for me as Arch has the AUR making packages that somehow not included in the repos super easy to install not to mention if you have Pacaur then it turns into one command! As i noticed this fact that i was now installing a pre-configured version of Arch on my PC i was kinda angry no not at the fact that it was an installer for arch and no not that it was pre-configured but by the fact that no one ever mentioned this distro to me back when i was using Arch a few weeks ago i must have spent a good two to four hours trying to find all the fonts i was missing and still never did if i might add! But putting all that aside Antergos as it stands right now is a great installer for Arch as it lets you choose your desktop environment installs all the fonts you’ll need to get started (Yes they’re still some missing but they are Japanese fonts so i can’t really fault them for not installing those) and i’m happy i did decide to try it as next time i install Arch I’ll most likely be using Antergos again!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2016 05:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/06/12/05-00-from-voidlinux-to-antergos-linux.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/06/12/05-00-from-voidlinux-to-antergos-linux.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remove The Port From A Minecraft Server IP</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DNS&lt;/strong&gt; It’s an amazing thing that without the internet would be no where near what it has become today. But today we’re going to focus on SRV and A Records as it’s how we can define IPs and ports using DNS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First a few definitions. We’ll start with an A Record. An A record is one of the most used type of DNS record and is used to simply define an IPv4 address that’s the “normal” type of IP address you’ll currently see and example being 127.0.0.1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up is the SRV record as it sounds a SRV record is a service record and is used to define a service on a network using priority’s and weights to allow some basic load balancing. The SRV record combines with an A or AAAA record to allow you to define an IP and a port of a specific service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now&lt;/strong&gt; that we know all that you should kinda get the idea of what I’m going to show you since all we have to do is set an A record pointing to you’re minecraft servers IP and then setup a minecraft SRV record to point to your A record!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well before we start you’ll need two things. A minecraft server and a domain. If you don’t have a domain depending on what you want it might only cost 1$ USD/Year so if you don’t have one yet since i will be using name.com since i know they work for this and i already have a domain with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright now that you have your domain we need to setup an A record pointing to your minecraft servers IP this is super simple simply pick a sub domain like mc.yourdomain.com and add you servers IP as so
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.frgl.pw/blog/16/1.png&quot; alt=&quot;a record&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of right now you should be able to connect to your server using mc.yourdomain.com:25566 (Where 25566 is your port number).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the SRV record this is slightly harder but still nice and easy only difference is  you now have 7 fields to fill in. For the service type we want “minecraft” for the protocol we want tcp for weight we want 10 for the port you’ll want to put your servers port in there for the target you’ll want to put your domain in there (The mc.yourdomain.com) in the TTL field we want 300 (seconds) and finally for the priority we want 10. at the end it should look like this:
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.frgl.pw/blog/16/2.png&quot; alt=&quot;srv record&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now if everything was done right you should be able to jump back into minecraft and use mc.yourdomain.com to connect to your server! now you can have a pretty domain for your server with out paying for port 25565! :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 08:33:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/06/08/08-33-remove-the-port-from-a-minecraft-server-ip.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/06/08/08-33-remove-the-port-from-a-minecraft-server-ip.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dual PC Live Streaming</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dual PC Streaming&lt;/strong&gt; Who is it for?. Dual PC streaming is for professional streamers who want the best quilty for their stream that current encoding tech allows for but at the same time allow them to get maintain a high frame rate on their main gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok. Now How does it work? Well their are several ways to setup dual PC streaming the first being the one i recommend is using a capture card on your gaming PC and sending the output to the stream PC along with an audio cable coming from your gaming PC into the streaming PC. Why do i recommend you doing it this way? easy dual pc streaming i with this method adds zero extra load to your gaming PC as it’s duties stay the exact same. It can’t be all good right? Well dual PC streaming using this method isn’t all good for the obvious reason that it is very expensive to get into and would require you to have a fully functional PC with a screen and some way for you to easily control it while streaming but beyond that there really is none.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the second option i’m going to talk about in this post. This one is a lot more complicated to setup and only really is useful of you simply want to compress the stream some more before sending it. For this setup you need of course two PCs but now the streaming PC doesn’t need a GPU or a screen even as all it does is host a NGINX-RTMP server and run FFMPEG both of which are controlled from the command line. The full setup of this method looks like such you have your Gaming PC with OBS running on it streaming at an absurdly high bitrate like 100,000 Kbps for example with near zero encoding but instead of streaming to twitch you stream to the local second PC that then ingests the feed uses its processing power to compress the video feed to something reasonable like 2,500 Kbps and send it to twitch. Would i recommend this? Well if you happen to have a second PC lying around ya go for it as the only real negative effect on your stream will be the slight bit of extra delay (1-2 Sec~). Would i recommend someone go out and buy a new PC for this? No unless you have money to burn and really want to get all you can out of both of those PCs or have a really slow upload. Plus if you have money to burn you might as well go all out and setup the much much better first example!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, comments or anything feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#109;&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#111;&amp;#112;&amp;#115;&amp;#046;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 16:58:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://boops.me/2016/06/04/16-58-dual-pc-live-streaming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://boops.me/2016/06/04/16-58-dual-pc-live-streaming.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
